Return to a galaxy far far away.
Return of the Jedi is a adventure, action, science
fiction film directed by Richard Marquand.
Luke Skywalker leads a mission to rescue his friend Han Solo from the clutches of Jabba the Hutt, the Emperor prepares to crush
the Rebellion with a more powerful Death Star, and the Rebel fleet mounts a massive attack on the space station.
Luke Skywalker confronts Darth Vader in a final
climactic duel before the evil Emperor.
Luke Skywalker, played by Mark Hamill.
Han Solo, played by Harrison Ford.
Princess Leia, played by Carrie Fisher.
Lando Calrissian, played by Billy Dee Williams.
C-3PO, played by Anthony Daniels.
Chewbacca, played by Peter Mayhew.
Return of the Jedi (also known as Star Wars: Episode VI – Return of the Jedi)  is a 1983 American epic space
opera film directed by Richard Marquand from a screenplay by Lawrence Kasdan and George Lucas.
The sequel to The Empire Strikes Back (1980), it is the third installment in the original
Star Wars trilogy and the sixth chronological film in the "Skywalker Saga".
The film follows the ongoing struggle between the malevolent Galactic
Empire and the freedom fighters of the Rebel Alliance.
As the rebels attempt to destroy the Empire's second Death Star, Luke Skywalker tries
to bring his father, Darth Vader, back from the dark side of the Force.
The film stars Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Billy Dee Williams,
Anthony Daniels, David Prowse, Kenny Baker, Peter Mayhew, and Frank Oz.
Steven Spielberg, David Lynch, and David Cronenberg were considered to
direct the film before Marquand signed on as director.
The production team relied on Lucas' storyboards during pre-production.
While writing the shooting script, Lucas, Kasdan, Marquand, and producer Howard
Kazanjian spent two weeks in conference discussing ideas to construct it.
Kazanjian's schedule pushed shooting to begin a few weeks early to allow Industrial
Light & Magic more time to work on the film's effects in post-production.
Filming took place in England, California, and Arizona
from January to May 1982 (1982-05).
Return of the Jedi was released in theaters by 20th Century-Fox on May 25, 1983.
It grossed $374 million worldwide during its initial theatrical
run, becoming the highest-grossing film of 1983.
It was well received by critics, with strong praise going to the performances of the
actors, John Williams' score, the special effects and the action sequences.
Several re-releases and revisions to the film have followed over the
decades, which have brought its total gross to $482 million.
The United States Library of Congress selected it for
preservation in the National Film Registry in 2021.
A prequel trilogy, released between 1999 and 2005, and a sequel
trilogy, released between 2015 and 2019, followed.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, sibling
relationship, rebel, emperor, space battle.
The tone is thought_provoking.